A Guide to the Grounds and Buildings Specifications, 1921-1962
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Grounds and Buildings Specifications, 1921-1962
The Library of Virginia
29261
1 cu. ft. (1 box)
Virginia Department of General Services, Department of Property Records and Insurance
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 29261 was transferred from the Department of Property Records and Insurance on September 10, 1976.
Historical Information
Agency history record (0008-24560) describes the history and functions of the Virginia Dept. of General Services. (Search as a/Virginia Dept. of General Services).
Scope and Content
Contains buildings and grounds specifications for state agencies and institutions, including the Capitol building, Motor Vehicle building, Central Highway Office building, State Finance building, and the State Library, among others.
Arrangement
This collection is minimally processed and materials are arranged with respect to original order.
Contents List
- Box 1,., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  - Extension to steel quonset hut used by the Central Garage, Richmond, Virginia, Job No. 8046-122-34 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cleaning Monuments and/or statues located in the Capitol Square and at Monument Avenue and Allen Avenues, Richmond, Virginia for the Commonwealth of Virginia, Job No. 1614-122-2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Extension to steel Quonset hut used by Central Garage, Richmond, Virginia, Job No. 8046-122-34 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Specifications for demolition of the Rountree building located on the south-east corner of Broad and Fourteenth Streets, Richmond, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Finish hardware, Commission No. 4817 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Specifications for inaugural platform - State Capitol, Richmond, Virginia for the Commonwealth of Virginia, Commission No. 1129, December 4, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Specifications for inaugural platform - State Capitol, Richmond, Virginia for the Commonwealth of Virginia, Commission #1129, December 4, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Painting specifications for the 1942-43 extension to Glen Lyn Plant (including old part of plant), Appalachian Electric Power Company, Glen Lyn, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General conditions and specifications for erection of archival building, Capitol Square, Richmond, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Contract between S.H. Gunn and the Commonwealth of Virginia, October 1921 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Specifications for reinforced concrete conduits, Capitol Grounds, Richmond, Virginia, September 27, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Specification for passenger elevator to be erected in Motor Vehicle Building - addition at 12th and Main Streets, Richmond, Virginia, Commission #802, May 24, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Motor Vehicle Building - addition (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Motor Vehicle Building - addition (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Specifications for concrete work, alterations to building at Richmond, Va. for Motor Vehicle Department, State of Virginia, May 18, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Repairs to the Real Estate Exchange Building, 815 East Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, for the Bernie Corporation, Richmond, Virginia, and the Commonwealth of Virginia Lessee, prepared by the Office of John J. Mattern, Jr., Architect, Richmond, Virginia, January 1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Painting (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Survey of offices located in the State Office Building, Capitol Building, and Library Building by Carneal, Johnston, and Wright for Hon. Harry Flood Byrd, January 15, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Extension to steel Quonset hut used by the Central Garage, Richmond, Virginia, Job No. 8046-122-34, December 19, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alterations to basement office space for the Department of the Treasury - Finance Building specifications for heating and air conditioning, February 23, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Specifications for air conditioning in the State Finance Building, Capitol Square, Richmond, Virginia, February 11, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Specification for installation of acoustical tile in certain space occupied by the Division of Planning and Economic Development, Third Floor, State Finance Building, Richmond, Virginia, August 20, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Specification for self-contained air conditioning unit, State Treasurer's Office, I.B.M. Room, basement, State Finance Building, Capitol Square, Richmond, Virginia, May 22, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Specifications for asphalt tile floor covering and movable steel partitions, Alteration A, Second Floor, State Finance Building, Division of Purchase and Printing, Richmond, Virginia, March 5, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Border and foundation planting for the Capitol Square, Job No. 7831-122-31, December 12, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Specification for sprinkler system, Finance Building, Capitol Square, Richmond, Virginia, January 10, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Specifications for air conditioning space occupied by the State Compensation Board, Second Floor, State Finance Building, Capitol Square, Richmond, Virginia, July 8, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Specifications for air conditioning system, Third Floor, State Finance Building, Capitol Square, Richmond, Virginia, March 26, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Acoustical - asphalt tile installation, State Finance Building., Auditor of Public Accounts, Richmond, Virginia, February 20, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Specifications for "Improvements to basement space, State Finance Building, Richmond, Virginia", June 14, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Specifications for alterations to elevator shaftway, State Finance Building, Richmond, Virginia, Work Order No. 25217, September 3, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Specifications for window washing in buildings listed located in Richmond, Virginia, for Commonwealth of Virginia, Division of the Budget, Section of Grounds and Buildings, State Finance Building, Richmond, Virginia, Work Order No. 41572, June 26, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Specifications for air conditioning Room 105, State Finance Building, June 13, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Specifications for alterations to State Office Building No. 5, 1322-28 East Grace Street, Richmond, Virginia, February 6, 1956 (Box 1, Box 34)
  - Specifications for additional exhaust and air conditioning, Stock Feed Laboratory, 1300 East Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, September 4, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Alterations to 1300 East Franklin St. Richmond, Virginia for the Commonwealth of Virginia, Commission No. 5001, May 23, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Alterations to 1300 East Franklin St. Richmond, Virginia for the Commonwealth of Virginia, Commission No. 5001, May 23, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Specifications for air conditioning, Feed Laboratory, 1300 East Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, June 2, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Specifications for air conditioning - Second Floor, Office Building No. 4, 1308 - 10 East Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, March 11, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Specifications for air conditioning - Second Floor, Office Building Number 4, 1308-10 East Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, July 15, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Specifications for air conditioning - Second Floor, Office Building No. 4, 1308-10 East Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, April 17, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Specifications for air conditioning - Second Floor, Office Building No. 4, 1308-10 East Franklin Street, Richmond, Virginia, March 11, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Specifications for alterations to building 1308-10 E. Franklin Street, Department of Agriculture, Richmond, Virginia, April 15, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Specification for air conditioning for Gasoline Laboratory, 102 North Governor Street, Richmond, Virginia, October 25, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Specifications for air conditioning installation, State Office Building No. 8, 201 Governor Street, Richmond, Virginia, May 23, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Specifications for alterations to State office Building No. 5, 1322-28 East Grace Street, Richmond, Virginia, February 6, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Specifications for movable wood partitions, 1405 East Grace Street, State Board of Education, Richmond, Virginia, March 18, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Specification for elimination of vibration of air conditioning machinery, Central Highway Building, 1221 East Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, July 30, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Specifications for summer-winter air conditioning system, basement - I.B.M. Room, Highway Building, Richmond, Virginia, October 8, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Specifications for air conditioning of Room No. 1, basement, Central Highway Office Building, 1221 East Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, March 1, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Specifications for Repointing cut limestone and granite, Central Highway Office Building, Richmond Virginia, April 19, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Specifications for replacement of utility pipe lines - for laboratories and other services involved, Central Highway Office Building, Richmond, Virginia, October 6, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Specifications for providing an additional exit for auditorium of Central Highway Office Building, Richmond, Virginia, September 18, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Specification for air conditioning equipment for Central Highway Office Building, Richmond, Virginia, May 15, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Specifications for air conditioning system for the Central Highway Office Building, Richmond, Virginia, for the Department of Highways, Commonwealth of Virginia, Commission #950, May 20, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Specifications for air conditioning system for the Central Highway Office Building, Richmond, Virginia, for the Department of Highways, Commonwealth of Virginia, Commission #950, May 20, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Specifications for heating, ventilating, and air conditioning, Virginia State Library, Richmond, Virginia, August 24, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Specifications for alterations and additions to air conditioning and heating systems in State Library and Supreme Court of Appeals Building for the Commonwealth of Virginia in Richmond, Virginia, Commission No. 1388, November 12, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Specifications for boilers and stokers to be installed in the Central Power Plant of the State Library Building, Richmond, Virginia, for the Commonwealth of Virginia, February 1939 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Cutline description, rewiring, State Library Building, Richmond, Virginia, October 17, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Steel shelving specification, State Library Building, Richmond, Virginia, Commission #702 (Box 1, Folder 61)